uwstout.edu 2019-04-25

# University of Wisconsin-Stout Privacy Statement | University of Wisconsin - Stout

The University of Wisconsin-Stout collects a variety of information through this website. UW-Stout is the sole owner of all information collected through this site, and it does not sell, share, rent, or otherwise disclose this information except as described in this statement. Information may be collected at various points on the site and may change without notice. Use of this website is voluntary. By using this website, you agree to allow UW-Stout to collect and use any information you provide using the site, including personally identifiable information (“PII”) and non-personal information as described in this Privacy Statement.  

**Collection and Use of Non-personal Information:  **Such information cannot be used to identify an individual personally. It is used to monitor site usage, health, and effectiveness, and it is also used to make improvements to the functionality and organization of the site. Non-personal information that may be collected and used includes, but is not limited to:  

  * The Internet Protocol (IP) address and name of the Internet domain used to access the Internet 
  * The IP address of the website that referred the user to the UW-Stout web site  

  * The date and time of access  

  * The pages visited  

  * The web browser and operating system used to access the web site  

  * Search terms used on the site

**Collection of Personal information:**  Users may choose to voluntarily provide information on the site that could be used to identify them personally. This information is strictly voluntary – no personal information is collected unless the user provides it. Personal information that may be collected includes, but is not limited to:  

  * Contact information  

  * Employment information and history  

  * Education history  

  * References  

  * Gift information  

  * University affiliation  

  * Information provided through online forms for a variety of purposes

For information on student privacy rights and our compliance to the Federal Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA), please refer to [information hosted by our Registrar's Office](https://www.uwstout.edu/academics/academic-services/registration-and-records-office/registration-and-records-policies/student-record-information).

**Use of Personal Information:  **UW-Stout may use your personal information like that described above for the following purposes (this list may change without notice):  

  * Administer users’ participation in this web site  

  * Communicate information that may be of interest to users  

  * Fulfill requests for services or materials  

  * Contact users  

  * Confirm information provided by users  

  * Process gifts  

  * Conduct research or surveys  

  * Respond to subpoenas, court orders or legal process  

  * Facilitate interactions with third parties

**Sharing Personal Information:  **Personal information provided to UW-Stout through this web site may be available to employees of the University or to authorized third parties who provide services to the University or to the users of this web site ([www.uwstout.edu](http://www.uwstout.edu/)). Select third parties may be provided with personal information from this web site to help the University fulfill its mission. UW-Stout will take reasonable steps to ensure that these third parties are obligated to protect personal information on its behalf.

### **Collection Methods**

UW-Stout may use various technologies such as cookies (small text files installed or updated when a web site is visited), applets, scripts, server logs, custom URL parameters, tracking images, information and correspondence, or web analytics to collect information. Depending on your browser you may be able to disable certain collection methods. This may limit your ability to use some features of this website.

Third party vendors, including Google, may use cookies on our Site. 

We use the Google AdWords remarketing service-including the DoubleClick cookie and remarketing pixels-to advertise on third party sites (including Google) to previous visitors to our site. It could mean that we advertise to previous visitors who haven't completed a task on our site, for example using the contact form to make an inquiry. This could be in the form of an advertisement on the Google search results page, or a site in the Google Display Network. Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on someone's past visits to the Site. Of course, any data collected will be used in accordance with our own privacy statement and [Google's policy](https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/143465).

_Opting  out:_ You can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the [Google Ad Preferences](http://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/) page or the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). 

We also use certain Google Analytics features-including remarketing and advertising reporting features that leverage cookies and tracking pixels-to monitor user behavior on our site and to better target our advertising efforts. 

_Opting  out:_ You can [install a browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) to opt out of Google Analytics tracking.

**Links to Other Sites:**  UW-Stout may provide links to other, third-party web sites from this site. Any such sites are regulated by the privacy policies of the providers of those web sites and not by this privacy statement. UW-Stout is not responsible for the privacy practices, security, or content of any third-party sites.  Your use of non-Stout websites is subject to the terms and conditions or privacy statements of the providers of those websites.

### How We Protect Your Information

We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our Site.

Sensitive and private data exchange between the Site and its Users happens over an SSL-secured communication channel.

### Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this Site or your experiences with this Site, or GDPR-related questions and requests, please contact us at:

Learning and Information Technology  
University of Wisconsin-Stout  
121 10th Avenue E   
Menomonie, WI, 54751

Or e-mail [helpdesk.uwstout.edu](mailto:helpdesk.uwstout.edu)  
715-232-5000

Privacy Statement last updated on Friday, March 8, 2019 at 10:00 AM.
